# PHANIKUMAR S TATA

#### Currently searching for a R programming position

I am a Clinical programmer using SAS software, have more then 14 years of working experience using SAS programming to generate tables/listings and graphs. Extensive experience working for CRO'S and Pharmaceutical companies

I made this resume using pagedown package. If you are interested in my background and skills, please feel free to contact me.



### CONTACT INFO

- tataphani@gmail.com
- github.com/Phanikumar
- **J** +1 512-621-5484
- ResearchGate

in Linkedin

♠ Professional Blog

For more information, please contact me via email.

## **HOBBIES**

Running

#### **SKILLS**

Experienced in doing statistical analysis, statistical learning models

Full experience in generation of Safety and Efficacy Table/Listings/figures for all Phases of Clinical trial data analysis.

Skill level

SAS Excellent

R Good

Python Learning

## **EDUCATION**

2000-2004

#### **University of Maryland**

M.S. in Information and Computing Sciences

Mary Land, US

Thesis: Commercial Implications of Bass hunting near Coastal areas of Wetlands

1998-2000

Osmania University - Department of Business Management

M.B.A in Market research

AP. India

Thesis: Effect of Micro financing on small scale sectors specially non branded sectors

1995-1998

**Osmania University** 

Bachelors in Maths, Statistics and Economics

AP, India

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2015-Present

#### Principal Statistical programmer,

#### Syneos Health

- · Created Safety and efficacy reports as requested by statisticians. Working on
- North Carolina State, United States
- · Wrote Shiny app demos.
- · Converted statistical tutorials from SAS to R language.
- · Taught R language to beginners.

June 2009-November 2010

#### Contract Statistical programmer,

#### Biogen IDEC

- · Reviewed and Validated TLF's generated by CRO's
- · Created Safety and efficacy reports as requested by
- Q California, United States
- statisticians.
- Generated/Validated Nonmem (PK/PD) datasets.

June 2008-November 2009

## Contract Statistical programmer,

#### **UCB Pharma**

- · Conversion of Legacy studies to FDA submissions
- Developed/Validated SAS programs/Macros for creating

#### Raleigh NC, United States

SDTM datasets

· Automated reports using SAS EXCILEPATH macros for folder location

# October 2007-November 2008

#### **Contract Statistical programmer,**

- Developed/Validated SAS programs/Macros for creating SDTM datasets
- Developed System macro using %SYSINFO

#### Feb 2006-October 2007

#### Contract Statistical programmer,

Pharmaceutical product Development

- Austin TX, United States
- Developed/Validated SAS programs/Macros for creating SDTM datasets
- Developed System macro using %SYSINFO

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

2020

Introduction to R Studio Language for Beginners.

Instructor of R and R studio Training Courses at Carpenters. ♥ TX, US

2020

Introduction to R Language for Beginners.

Instructor of R and R studio Training Courses at Syneos Health.

TX, US

2002 | 2004 Macro economics.

Teaching assistant of Business school EC2-201 courses at UMD

MD, USA



Therapeutic Area	Project	Years of Experience
Oncology	Bayer	5
Auto Immune	Lilly	4
Diabetics	UCB, PPD	3
Pain	Progenics	1

Project Experience